<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">

  <title>Searching</title>  

  <para>Once the indexing process is started and some data has been
  indexed, you can start to perform searches against the Sensei cluster.
  A search query is done by building a Sensei request and sending it to
  a Sensei broker.  You can do this using a native Java Sensei client,
  or other client APIs that support other languages like Python or
  JavaScript.</para>

  <para>Upon receiving a request, a Sensei broker passes it to a set of
  selected Sensei nodes, merges the search results from these nodes, and
  then returns the merged results back to the requester.  What set of
  Sensei nodes are selected for a request is decided using load
  balancer.  Based on the need of the applications, you can plug in
  different customized load balancers.  By default, Sensei uses a load
  balancer that distributes work load based on consistent
  hashing.</para>

  <section>
    <title>Sensei Request</title>

    <para>A Sensei request contains the following main
    parameters:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Query: the input query string</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Offset: the starting offset of search results</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Count: the number of search results to return</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Initializing parameters for runtime facet handlers: a map
        that contains the initializing parameters that are needed by all
        runtime facet handlers</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Flag indicating whether stored fields are to be
        fetched</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Partitions: shards of the index to be searched</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Flag indicating whether explanation information should be returned</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Routing parameter: the field value used for routing</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Group-by field: the field name used for the group-by
        operation (also called <emphasis>field collapsing <indexterm> 
        <primary>field collapsing</primary>
        </indexterm></emphasis>)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Load Balancing</title>

    <para>(To be finished)</para>
  </section>

</chapter>
